Joe Senior

4 Dragon crescent, Leeds, West Yorkshire LS12 4AZ Phone: 07703582386 E-Mail: joesenior07@gmail.com

Personal profile

Hello, my name is Joe Senior and I am currently working for NHS digital as an 2nd line technical engineer. I have over 10 years' experience in Linux and windows technologies. I have exceptional knowledge of Linux and monitoring technologies.

In my past experiences, I have learned interpersonal skills, which include dealing with all types of stakeholders including company directors, Also I have many industry certifications including Splunk Certified and have achieved an MCSA SQL server 2012. I am also studying towards the AWS System operations certification at this moment in time.

Experience

NHS Digital

2nd line Technical operations Team leader

17.06.2019 - Present

As well as my duties in the technical operations team which are bellow, I am in charge of managing and mentoring a team of 4 in both technical and non-technical issues and with motivating my team in order for them to perform at their best for the organisation

2nd line Technical operations operator

07.08.2017 -17.06.2019

At NHS Digital, I am a 2nd Technical operations analyst where we monitor the NHS spine applications for example the E-referral service and GP2GP. My day to day role is monitoring the NHS spine applications as well as looking into performance issues on the database side, the database technologies that we use at NHS Digital are RIAK and PostgreSQL, I also have extensive experience in Linux from Redhat to Ubuntu in an enterprise setting. I have vast experience in using Splunk for searching, reporting and creating dashboards to monitor performance which enables proactive monitoring of various programmes including Spine core, ERS and CIS.

I also have experience in creating monitoring solutions using Nagios, Splunk and Grafana and I have some AWS experiencing in creating EC2 Instances, VPC, S3 storage buckets, handling roles via IAM and ELB (elastic load balancer). I also have some experience in creating Docker images and containers and in Kubernetes setting up a two node Kubernetes setup and have created pods, deployments and services.

I have team management experience for example when team leader of the shift was away, I handled the team Rota in order to make sure the team had done all the tasks and BAU required and had documented this and made sure all the details were in the handover for the next shift.

I also have experience in many web server technologies including Nginx for installing, configuring and deploying as a load balancer as well as installing SSL certificates and redirecting HTTP traffic to HTTPS traffic.

Liquid Logic

2nd line Technical operations analyst

27.10.2016-28.07.2017

I work as part of a team in supporting customers using the Liquid-Logic adult's software (LAS) this includes troubleshooting server side issues, logging and replicating bugs in accordance with ITIL procedures, writing custom SQL scripts as and when required, I deal with the issues as and when they are reported and are dealt within SLA.

I also deal with the SQL server data warehouse troubleshooting issues with blocked SQL causing data warehouse failures and data Quality issues. Also, I do upgrades and installations in terms of the bespoke Liquid-Logic software.

NHS Digital

07.09.2015 -24.10.2016

2nd line Technical operations operator

At NHS Digital, I am a 2nd Technical operations analyst where we monitor the NHS spine applications for example the E-referral service and GP2GP. My day to day role is monitoring the NHS spine applications as well as looking into performance issues on the database side, the database technologies that we use at HSCIC are RIAK and PostgreSQL, I also have extensive experience in Linux from Redhat to Ubuntu in an enterprise setting.

Emis Healthcare

23.06.2011-03.09.2015

Hosted operation analyst

26.01.2015-03.09.2015

I am in charge of monitoring 3000 virtual machines via hyper V which run windows server 2012 R2 and 6000 database instances running SQL server 2012, also I troubleshoot SQL server, Queries, Query plan and system performance in order reduce performance issues. Also, I look into performance metrics for example disk space, processor usage, SQL paging health and high memory usage. Also, I have used SSIS to create packages to be run as a SQL server agent job and SSRS in order to create reports and dashboards to be used internally.

1ST/2ND line support analyst

23.06.2011-23.01.2015

At Emis healthcare I am a support consultant where I am dealing with all types of customers within the UK. Some issues that I deal with is resetting passwords in IIS and active directory, assessing event logs to see the cause of issues and working to SLA's. One of my main roles is to troubleshoot connectivity issues between servers and desktop PC's using commands including nslookup to diagnose DNS issues. Also, one of the main programs that I use in my role is Microsoft management studio for basic SQL queries.

Barratts priceless limited

18.10.2010-18.06.2011

1ST/2ND line support analyst

18.10.2010-18.06.2011

At BPL shoes I have been involved with windows server administration, ghosting computers in an efficient way and I have been able to develop an array of IT skills and troubleshooting techniques which include phone troubleshooting support as well as remote connection support via remote desktop connection and VNC. Also, I was responsible for setting up new users at the company and setting up Blackberry smart phones via the Blackberry enterprise server. In this job role I was supporting 100 users on site and 200 users remotely who used secure checkpoint VPN however I do have experience with Cisco ASA devices.

One of my main tasks was to look after active directory to make sure the objects, groups and containers were setup correctly and to make sure that new users had an exchange account for outlook and were setup in the correct mailing lists.

Education Leeds

17.07.2008-20.09.2010

While working at education Leeds as a support technician I was in charge of creating new user accounts for students using active directory for windows and also creating accounts via mac OSX server. One of my main duties was to prepare new PC and MAC OSX devices which involved making sure they had the correct software for the purpose and that they were audited on the internal system.

Education

Joseph priestly college 1.09.2008- 1.09.2010

BTEC national for ICT practitioners (ABB)

Adult numeracy Maths (C)

Adult literacy English (C)

Wortley high school 1.09.2001-1.09.2008

Wortley high school - GCE ICT (Pass)

Cisco IT essentials 2 networking (C)

Cisco IT essentials 1 PC hardware and software (C)

GCE Media (Pass)

GNVQ ICT (C)

GNVQ Media and communications (C)

GCSE Maths (pass)

GCSE English (pass)

Microsoft Certifications

MTA Database essentials 14.07.2014

Microsoft Certified Professional 14.07.2014

Querying in SQL server 2012 03.06.2015

Administrating SQL server 2012/2014 database 17/03/2016

Implementing a data warehouse in Microsoft SQL server 2012/2014 12/07/2016

MCSA SQL server 2012/2014 12/07/2016

Splunk Certifications

Splunk Certified User 16/08/2018

Skills

Technical Skills: Mac OS (Advanced), Windows Server 2012 R2 Clustering services administration (Intermediate), Windows server 2012 R2 server administration (Intermediate), Installing and configuring hyper V (intermediate), installing guest operating systems on a host of Hyper V (intermediate), working with VMware VSphere (intermediate), Microsoft SQL Server 2012 administration (Intermediate), Microsoft SQL Server 2012 troubleshooting performance (Intermediate), Backing up an restoring SQL databases (intermediate), SSIS (intermediate), SSRS (intermediate), Managing jobs with SQL server 2102 server agent (intermediate), Configuring SQL server instances (intermediate), installing SQL server 2012 (intermediate), working with SQL profiler to resolve performance issues in SQL (Intermediate), working with extended events in SQL server 2012 in order to resolve performance issues (intermediate), Troubleshooting T-SQL Queries (Intermediate), Writing Stored Procedures in T-SQL (Intermediate), Writing functions in T-SQL (Microsoft SQL server 2012 always on (Intermediate), Using windows server 2012 performance monitor to look into in-depth system issues and offer resolutions (Intermediate), monitoring system Centre 2012 R2 (intermediate), ITIL processes and procedures (intermediate), Splunk querying (advanced), Designing and implementing Splunk operational dashboards (advanced).